<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A²R Lab</title>
    <link>https://a2r-lab.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on A²R Lab</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; {year} Brian Plancher</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://a2r-lab.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This list includes publications from the PI&amp;rsquo;s time at the Harvard &lt;a href=&#34;https://agile.seas.harvard.edu/&#34;&gt;Agile Robotics&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://edge.seas.harvard.edu/&#34;&gt;Edge Computing&lt;/a&gt; Labs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Projects</title>
      <link>https://a2r-lab.github.io/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://a2r-lab.github.io/projects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our lab&amp;rsquo;s core research question is: &lt;em&gt;how can we construct computational systems that enable robots to intelligently, flexibility, and reliably operate in the field?&lt;/em&gt; We seek to address this problem by &lt;strong&gt;developing, optimizing, implementing, and evaluating next-generation algorithms and edge computational systems, at all scales, through algorithm-hardware-software co-design&lt;/strong&gt;. This approach requires designing theoretically sound optimization- and learning-based algorithms (e.g., model predictive control) that run at order-of-magnitude faster rates on edge computational hardware ranging from small-scale MCUs, to large-scale GPUs and FPGAs, and even to custom ASICs and non von Neumann architectures (e.g., neuromorphic processors). As such, we work across the computational stack, designing algorithms, software systems, and computational hardware at the intersection of robotics, optimization, computer architecture / systems, and machine learning. At the same time we work to promote responsible and accessible robotics and computing. We therefore research ways to better understand and improve diversity, equity, inclusion, and belonging in STEM education globally; promote a sustainable and privacy preserving future for autonomous systems and edge computing; as well as design and teach new interdisciplinary, project-based, open-access courses that lower the barrier to entry of cutting edge topics like robotics, parallel programming, and embedded machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://a2r-lab.github.io/people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://a2r-lab.github.io/people/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A²R Lab at ICRA 2024</title>
      <link>https://a2r-lab.github.io/icra-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://a2r-lab.github.io/icra-24/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;paper-presentations-and-posters&#34;&gt;Paper Presentations and Posters&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday 10:30am-12:00pm&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; Poster Session Tuesday 1:30pm-3:00pm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://a2r-lab.org/publication/tinympc/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TinyMPC: Model-Predictive Control on Resource-Constrained Microcontrollers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (TuAA1-CC.1 - Award Session - CC-Main Hall)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday 1:30pm-3:00pm&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; Poster Session Tuesday 4:30pm-6:00pm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://a2r-lab.org/publication/diffcompressdrl/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Differentially Encoded Observation Spaces for Perceptive Reinforcement Learning&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (TuBT8-CC.7 - Reinforcement Learning I - CC-418)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday 10:30am-12:00pm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://a2r-lab.org/publication/robotperf/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RobotPerf: An Open-Source, Vendor-Agnostic, Benchmarking Suite for Evaluating Robotics Computing System Performance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (WeAT20-NT.8 - Performance Evaluation and Benchmarking - NT-G302)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday 1:30pm-3:00pm&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; Poster Session Wednesday 4:30pm-6:00pm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://a2r-lab.org/publication/symstair/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Symmetric Stair Preconditioning of Linear Systems for Parallel Trajectory Optimization&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (WeBT18-AX.3 - Optimization and Optimal Control I - AX-206)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://a2r-lab.org/publication/mpcgpu/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MPCGPU: Real-Time Nonlinear Model Predictive Control through Preconditioned Conjugate Gradient on the GPU&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (WeBT18-AX.4 - Optimization and Optimal Control I - AX-206)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;workshop-panels-and-presentations&#34;&gt;Workshop Panels and Presentations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday 4:30-6:00pm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.google.com/site/adrienescandehomepage/ICRA2024ClimateChange&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Workshop on Robots and Roboticists in the Age of Climate Change&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;ndash; Panel Discussion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join Us</title>
      <link>https://a2r-lab.github.io/join/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://a2r-lab.github.io/join/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We are unfortunately &lt;strong&gt;full for Spring and Summer 2025&lt;/strong&gt;. Please check back at the start of next semester for more term-time research options.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are always looking to grow our team! We are looking for students across all levels of experience: from undergraduates, to Masters students, to PhD candidates, to Postdoctoral researchers. No background in robotics, parallel programming, or machine learning is required. That said, we are generally conducting research that requires mathematical maturity and programming and so we will expect some CS / EE / Math background. For CU and BC undergraduates considering taking &lt;strong&gt;COMS BC3159: Parallel Optimization for Robotics&lt;/strong&gt; as it is perfect preperation for much of the lab&amp;rsquo;s research (and the course project is a perfect way to start to explore our research)! Other useful courses include: COMS W3157 Advanced Programming, CSEE 3827: Fundamentals of Computer Systems, or any courses in optimization, numerical methods, or robotics!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, we are looking for students who demonstrate commitment, creativity, communication skills, and courage to learn something new. We also particularly encourage students from any of the underrepresented groups in CS and Engineering to reach out about potential projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Undergraduate and Masters part-time researchers during the academic semester, in order to ensure that you can have a meaningful research experience as a member of the lab we expect you to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Commit at least 9 hours per week to your research work (similar to a 3-credit college course &amp;ndash; note that Barnard/Columbia students can receive course credit under COMS BC3099/W3998/W4901/W6901)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide a (team) progress update every week either during lab meetings, at office hours, or through a scheduled meeting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are also additional opportunites for full-time summer research experiences. For Barnard students, consider applying for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://barnard.edu/summer-research-institute&#34;&gt;Summer Research Institute (SRI)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, comments, or concerns, please reach out to us at: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:barnard.a2r.lab@gmail.com&#34;&gt;barnard.a2r.lab@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;faqs&#34;&gt;FAQs:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What kinds of research is the lab doing right now?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find descriptions of some of our current research directions on our &lt;a href=&#34;https://a2r-lab.github.io/projects&#34;&gt;projects page&lt;/a&gt; as well as our recent publications on our &lt;a href=&#34;https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication&#34;&gt;publications page&lt;/a&gt;. In general we tend to explore one of two things. First, how to combine algorithmic and computer hardware insights to accelerate robotics problems. You can find a talk exploring these concepts &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IFXlHAfr_v0&#34;&gt;at this link&lt;/a&gt;. Second, how to increase the accessibility of cutting-edge computer science topics globally. This is best exemplified by our work with &lt;a href=&#34;https://tinymledu.org/&#34;&gt;TinyMLedu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is the position paid?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are doing research through a funded research program you will be funded (e.g., PhD program, SRI summer program). For Barnard and Columbia students there are lists of possible term-time and summer funded research programs at the following links: &lt;a href=&#34;https://barnard.edu/student-research-programs&#34;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://studentresearch.engineering.columbia.edu/content/student-resources&#34;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cc-seas.columbia.edu/scholars/archive/events/ceep/klugefellows&#34;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.careereducation.columbia.edu/programs/columbia-college-summer-funding-program&#34;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.careereducation.columbia.edu/programs/columbia-engineering-internship-fund&#34;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://urf.columbia.edu/fellowship/laidlaw-scholars-program&#34;&gt;[6]&lt;/a&gt;. There is also a large list of national research fellowships &lt;a href=&#34;https://urf.columbia.edu/opportunity/search&#34;&gt;at this link&lt;/a&gt;. If you do not have a research fellowship we will be constantly applying for grants to support additional student researchers, however, depending on timing, we may only be able to offer research as an independent study for credit. However, do note that you can receive elective credit towards the CS major for research done through independent studies! &lt;strong&gt;Note: We do not expect you to be funded to join the lab! We can work to help you get funded AFTER you join! Also if you reach out ahead of time we can work together to get you funded BEFORE you start doing research.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Does research happen all the time?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, in fact, the summer is often the busiest time of the year for research! So whether you have interest and time in the sping, summer, or fall, there will always be opportunities for research!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why should I consider doing research?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research is a great way to learn more about a field of interest and develop both your technical and communication skills. Also, whether you are considering graduate school or industry positions, spending a few semesters doing research and publishing a peer-reviewed paper and/or presenting at regional and national conferences looks great on your resume!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you have any resources for getting started?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While most research projects will dive deep into specific areas of robotics and so there aren&amp;rsquo;t truly general resources that are applicale to all projects, as most (current) projects do explore hardware acceleration and optimal control to some degree, there are a few things you could do to prepare for research in the lab. First, as mentioned above, for CU and BC undergraduates considering taking my course, COMS BC 3159: Parallel Optimization for Robotics, and for CU masters students and PhDs consider TAing the course! Second, also as mentioned above, my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IFXlHAfr_v0&#34;&gt;talk at Barnard&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/tTy2Vhg2G-I&#34;&gt;PhD Dissertation Defense&lt;/a&gt; provide nice overviews of some projects I have done in the past (note that the Barnard talk is aimed at a more introductory audience). If you want to go deeper into the algorithms and math, Russ Tedrake&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://courses.edx.org/courses/MITx/6.832x/3T2014/info&#34;&gt;Underactuated Robotics&lt;/a&gt; course on edX covers many of those topics. If you want to learn more about GPU programming, &lt;a href=&#34;https://enccs.github.io/gpu-programming/&#34;&gt;this online course&lt;/a&gt; provides a nice introduction.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
