<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>1 on A²R Lab</title>
    <link>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication_types/1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 1 on A²R Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; {year} Brian Plancher</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication_types/1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>RobotCore: An Open Architecture for Hardware Acceleration in ROS 2</title>
      <link>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/robotcore/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/robotcore/</guid>
      <description>We introduce RobotCore, an architecture to integrate hardware acceleration in the widely-used ROS 2 robotics software framework. This architecture is target-agnostic (supports edge, workstation, data center, or cloud targets) and accelerator-agnostic (supports both FPGAs and GPUs). It builds on top of the common ROS 2 build system and tools and is easily portable across different research and commercial solutions through a new firmware layer. We also leverage the Linux Tracing Toolkit next generation (LTTng) for low-overhead real-time tracing and benchmarking. To demonstrate the acceleration enabled by this architecture, we design an intra-FPGA ROS 2 node communication queue to enable faster data flows, and use it in conjunction with FPGA-accelerated nodes to achieve a 24.42% speedup over a CPU.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tiny Robot Learning: Challenges and Directions for Machine Learning in Resource-Constrained Robots</title>
      <link>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/tinyrobotlearning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/tinyrobotlearning/</guid>
      <description>Tiny robot learning lies at the intersection of embedded systems, robotics, and ML, compounding the challenges of these domains. This paper gives a brief survey of the tiny robot learning space, elaborates on key challenges, and proposes promising opportunities for future work in ML system design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GRiD: GPU-Accelerated Rigid Body Dynamics with Analytical Gradients</title>
      <link>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/grid/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/grid/</guid>
      <description>We introduce and release GRiD, an open-source, GPU-accelerated library for computing rigid body dynamics with analytical gradients. GRiD was designed to accelerate nonlinear trajectory optimization through optimized code generation, GRiD provides as much as a 7.2x speedup over a state-of-the-art, multi-threaded CPU implementation and maintains as much as a 2.5x speedup when accounting for I/O overhead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robomorphic Computing: A Design Methodology for Domain-Specific Accelerators Parameterized by Robot Morphology</title>
      <link>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/robomorphic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/robomorphic/</guid>
      <description>We introduce robomorphic computing; a methodology to transform robot morphology into a customized hardware accelerator morphology. In this work, we (i) present this design methodology; (ii) use the methodology to generate a parameterized accelerator design for the gradient of rigid body dynamics; (iii) evaluate FPGA and synthesized ASIC implementations; and (iv) describe how the design can be automatically customized for other robot models. Our FPGA accelerator achieves speedups of 8x and 86x over CPU and GPU latency, and maintains an overall speedup of 1.9x to 2.9x deployed in an end-to-end coprocessor system. ASIC synthesis indicates an additional factor of 7.2x.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Performance Analysis of Parallel Differential Dynamic Programming on a GPU</title>
      <link>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/parallelddp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/parallelddp/</guid>
      <description>We analyze the benefits and tradeoffs of higher degrees of parallelization using a multiple-shooting variant of DDP implemented on a GPU. We describe our implementation strategy and present results demonstrating its performance compared to an equivalent multi-threaded CPU implementation using several benchmark control tasks. Our results suggest that GPU-based solvers can offer increased per-iteration computation time and faster convergence in some cases, but in general tradeoffs exist between convergence behavior and degree of algorithm-level parallelism. This work was &lt;a href=&#34;https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/parallelddp_icra&#34;&gt;extended&lt;/a&gt; and used for MPC on a physical Kuka arm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constrained Unscented Dynamic Programming</title>
      <link>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/cudp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/cudp/</guid>
      <description>We build on recent work on Unscented Dynamic Programming (UDP) - which eliminates dynamics derivative computations in DDP - to support general nonlinear state and input constraints using an augmented Lagrangian. The resulting algorithm has the same computational cost as first-order penalty-based DDP variants, but can achieve constraint satisfaction to high precision without the numerical ill-conditioning associated with penalty methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project-based, collaborative, algorithmic robotics for high school students: Programming self-driving race cars at MIT</title>
      <link>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/racecarteaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/racecarteaching/</guid>
      <description>We describe the pedagogy behind the MIT Beaver Works Summer Institute Robotics Program, a new high-school STEM program in robotics. The program utilizes state-of-the-art sensors and embedded computers for mobile robotics. The program was offered as a four-week residential program at MIT in the summer of 2016.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
