<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Edge ML on A²R Lab</title>
    <link>https://a2r-lab.github.io/tags/edge-ml/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Edge ML on A²R Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; {year} Brian Plancher</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://a2r-lab.github.io/tags/edge-ml/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Materiality and Risk in the Age of Pervasive AI Sensors</title>
      <link>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/materiality/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/materiality/</guid>
      <description>Artificial intelligence (AI) systems connected to sensor-laden devicesare becoming pervasive, which has notable implications for a range of AIrisks, including to privacy, the environment, autonomy and more. Thereis therefore a growing need for increased accountability around theresponsible development and deployment of these technologies. Herewe highlight the dimensions of risk associated with AI systems that arisefrom the material affordances of sensors and their underlying calculativemodels. We propose a sensor-sensitive framework for diagnosing theserisks, complementing existing approaches such as the US National Institute of Standards and Technology AI Risk Management Framework and the European Union AI Act, and discuss its implementation. We concludeby advocating for increased attention to the materiality of algorithmicsystems, and of on-device AI sensors in particular, and highlight the needfor development of a sensor design paradigm that empowers users andcommunities and leads to a future of increased fairness, accountability andtransparency.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI in the Developing World: How ‘Tiny Machine Learning’ can have a Big Impact</title>
      <link>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/tinymltheconversation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/tinymltheconversation/</guid>
      <description>The landscape of artificial intelligence (AI) applications has traditionally been dominated by the use of resource-intensive servers centralised in industrialised nations. However, recent years have witnessed the emergence of small, energy-efficient devices for AI applications, a concept known as tiny machine learning (TinyML). We’re most familiar with consumer-facing applications such as Siri, Alexa, and Google Assistant, but the limited cost and small size of such devices allow them to be deployed in the field. For example, the technology has been used to detect mosquito wingbeats and so help prevent the spread of malaria. It’s also been part of the development of low-power animal collars to support conservation efforts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Datasheets for Machine Learning Sensors</title>
      <link>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/mlsensorsdatasheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/mlsensorsdatasheet/</guid>
      <description>This paper introduces a standard datasheet template for ML sensors and discusses its essential components inluding: the system&amp;rsquo;s hardware, ML model and dataset attributes, end-to-end performance metrics, and environmental impact. We provide an example datasheet for our own ML sensor and discuss each section in detail. We highlight how these datasheets can facilitate better understanding and utilization of sensor data in ML applications, and we provide objective measures upon which system performance can be evaluated and compared.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Sensors: A Design Paradigm for the Future of Intelligent Sensors</title>
      <link>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/mlsensorscacm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/mlsensorscacm/</guid>
      <description>In this viewpoint we propose the ML sensor: a logical framework for developing ML-enabled embedded systems which empowers end users through its privacy-by-design approach. By limiting the data interface, the ML sensor paradigm helps ensure that no user information can be extracted beyond the scope of the sensor’s functionality. Our proposed definition is as follows: An ML sensor is a self-contained, embedded system that utilizes machine learning to process sensor data on-device – logically decoupling data computation from the main application processor and limiting the data access of the wider system to high-level ML model outputs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is TinyML Sustainable? Assessing the Environmental Impacts of Machine Learning on Microcontrollers</title>
      <link>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/sustainabletinyml/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/sustainabletinyml/</guid>
      <description>The sustained growth of carbon emissions and global waste elicits significant sustainability concerns for our environment&amp;rsquo;s future. The growing Internet of Things (IoT) has the potential to exacerbate this issue. However, an emerging area known as Tiny Machine Learning (TinyML) has the opportunity to help address these environmental challenges through sustainable computing practices. TinyML, the deployment of machine learning (ML) algorithms onto low-cost, low-power microcontroller systems, enables on-device sensor analytics that unlocks numerous always-on ML applications. This article discusses the potential of these TinyML applications to address critical sustainability challenges. Moreover, the footprint of this emerging technology is assessed through a complete life cycle analysis of TinyML systems. From this analysis, TinyML presents opportunities to offset its carbon emissions by enabling applications that reduce the emissions of other sectors. Nevertheless, when globally scaled, the carbon footprint of TinyML systems is not negligible, necessitating that designers factor in environmental impact when formulating new devices. Finally, research directions for enabling further opportunities for TinyML to contribute to a sustainable future are outlined.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
