<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A²R Lab</title>
    <link>https://a2r-lab.github.io/authors/behzadboroujerdian/</link>
    <description>Recent content on A²R Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; {year} Brian Plancher</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://a2r-lab.github.io/authors/behzadboroujerdian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>RoboRun: A Robot Runtime to Exploit Spatial Heterogeneity</title>
      <link>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/roborun/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/roborun/</guid>
      <description>This paper introduces RoboRun, a mobile-robot runtime that dynamically exploits the compute-environment synergy to improve performance and energy. We implement RoboRun in the Robot Operating System (ROS) and evaluate it on autonomous drones. We compare RoboRun against a state-of-the-art static design and show 4.5X and 4X improvements in mission time and energy, respectively, as well as a 36% reduction in CPU utilization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Compute in Autonomous Aerial Vehicles</title>
      <link>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/roleofcompute/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/roleofcompute/</guid>
      <description>By combining MAVBench (our tool-set, which consists of (1) a closed-loop real-time feedback simulator and (2) an end-to-end benchmark suite comprised of state-of-the-art kernels), analytical modeling, and an understanding of various compute impacts, we show up to 2X and 1.8X improvements for mission time and mission energy for two optimization case studies. Our investigations, as well as our optimizations, show that cyber-physical co-design, a methodology with which both the cyber and physical processes/quantities of the robot are developed with consideration of one another, similar to hardware-software co-design, is necessary for arriving at the design of the optimal robot.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
