<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>3 on A²R Lab</title>
    <link>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication_types/3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 3 on A²R Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; {year} Brian Plancher</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication_types/3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Code Generation for Conic Model-Predictive Control on Microcontrollers with TinyMPC</title>
      <link>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/conictinympc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/conictinympc/</guid>
      <description>We extend TinyMPC, an open-source, high-speed solver targeting low-power embedded control applications, to handle second-order cone constraints. We also present code-generation software to enable deployment of TinyMPC on a variety of microcontrollers. We benchmark our generated code against state-of-the-art embedded QP and SOCP solvers, demonstrating a two-order-of-magnitude speed increase over ECOS while consuming less memory. Finally, we demonstrate TinyMPC&amp;rsquo;s efficacy on the Crazyflie, a lightweight, resource-constrained quadrotor with fast dynamics. TinyMPC and its code-generation tools are publicly available at &lt;a href=&#34;https://tinympc.org/&#34;&gt;tinympc.org&lt;/a&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Materiality and Risk in the Age of Pervasive AI Sensors</title>
      <link>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/materiality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/materiality/</guid>
      <description>Artificial intelligence systems connected to sensor-laden devices are becoming pervasive, which has significant implications for a range of AI risks, including to privacy, the environment, autonomy, and more. In this paper, we provide a comprehensive analysis of the evolution of sensors, the risks they pose by virtue of their material existence in the world, and the impacts of ubiquitous sensing and on-device AI. We propose incorporating sensors into risk management frameworks and call for more responsible sensor and system design paradigms that address risks of such systems. We show through calculative models that current systems prioritize data collection and cost reduction and produce risks that emerge around privacy, surveillance, waste, and power dynamics. We then analyze these risks, highlighting issues of validity, safety, security, accountability, interpretability, and bias. We conclude by advocating for increased attention to the materiality of algorithmic systems, and of on-device AI sensors in particular, and highlight the need for development of a responsible sensor design paradigm that empowers users and communities and leads to a future of increased fairness, accountability and transparency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Datasheets for Machine Learning Sensors</title>
      <link>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/mlsensorsdatasheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/mlsensorsdatasheet/</guid>
      <description>This paper introduces a standard datasheet template for ML sensors and discusses its essential components inluding: the system&amp;rsquo;s hardware, ML model and dataset attributes, end-to-end performance metrics, and environmental impact. We provide an example datasheet for our own ML sensor and discuss each section in detail. We highlight how these datasheets can facilitate better understanding and utilization of sensor data in ML applications, and we provide objective measures upon which system performance can be evaluated and compared.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
