<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>3 on A²R Lab</title>
    <link>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication_types/3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 3 on A²R Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; {year} Brian Plancher</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication_types/3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Symmetric Stair Preconditioning of Linear Systems for Parallel Trajectory Optimization</title>
      <link>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/symstair/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/symstair/</guid>
      <description>In this work we present a new parallel-friendly symmetric stair preconditioner. We prove that our preconditioner has advantageous theoretical properties when used in conjunction with iterative methods for trajectory optimization such as a more clustered eigenvalue spectrum. Numerical experiments with typical trajectory optimization problems reveal that as compared to the best alternative parallel preconditioner from the literature, our symmetric stair preconditioner provides up to a 34% reduction in condition number and up to a 25% reduction in the number of resulting linear system solver iterations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Datasheets for Machine Learning Sensors</title>
      <link>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/mlsensorsdatasheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/mlsensorsdatasheet/</guid>
      <description>This paper introduces a standard datasheet template for ML sensors and discusses its essential components inluding: the system&amp;rsquo;s hardware, ML model and dataset attributes, end-to-end performance metrics, and environmental impact. We provide an example datasheet for our own ML sensor and discuss each section in detail. We highlight how these datasheets can facilitate better understanding and utilization of sensor data in ML applications, and we provide objective measures upon which system performance can be evaluated and compared.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
