<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>10 on A²R Lab</title>
    <link>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication_types/10/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 10 on A²R Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; {year} Brian Plancher</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication_types/10/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The 2025 Summer School on Optimization for Robotics</title>
      <link>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/optrobsummerschool2025ram/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/optrobsummerschool2025ram/</guid>
      <description>The 2025 Summer School on Optimization for Robotics took place on 14–18 July 2025 at the University of Patras in Patras, Greece. The event brought together researchers, students, and practitioners from across the world to learn, exchange ideas, and gain hands-on experience at the forefront of optimization methods for robotics. Overall, we had 89 total participants (∼7% undergraduate, ∼8% industry/engineer/faculty, ∼18% masters, and ∼66% Ph.D.) from more than 20 countries spanning four continents. The weeklong program featured a balanced mix of lectures, plenary talks, daily practical sessions, live demos, and social activities. The lectures covered foundational and advanced topics in optimization for planning, control, and learning in robotics, while the plenary speakers provided broad perspectives on emerging research directions and industrial applications.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Underrepresentation of Women in Robotics Research</title>
      <link>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/underrepresentationwomenram/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/underrepresentationwomenram/</guid>
      <description>Computer science (CS) and engineering research both have large and well documented gender diversity gaps. In fact, previous studies have reported that the overall CS Female Author Ratio (FAR) is only in the range of 16-26% and varies significantly between CS subfields ranging from as high as 42% in CS Education to as low as 8% in Theory and Algorithms. To understand the current state of gender diversity of robotics, we recently collected and analyzed the gender of paper authors from all IEEE RAS fully sponsored conferences (ARSO, CASE, HAPTICS, Humanoids, ICRA, ISAM, MEMS, RoboSoft, SIMPAR, SSRR) as well as IROS and RA-L from 2019-2021. Overall, we find that robotics has a long way to go to reach gender parity, with an overall FAR of only 11-12%. We hope this analysis helps the robotics community to continue to emphasize the importance of working to improve our diversity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Sensors: A Design Paradigm for the Future of Intelligent Sensors</title>
      <link>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/mlsensorscacm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/mlsensorscacm/</guid>
      <description>In this viewpoint we propose the ML sensor: a logical framework for developing ML-enabled embedded systems which empowers end users through its privacy-by-design approach. By limiting the data interface, the ML sensor paradigm helps ensure that no user information can be extracted beyond the scope of the sensor’s functionality. Our proposed definition is as follows: An ML sensor is a self-contained, embedded system that utilizes machine learning to process sensor data on-device – logically decoupling data computation from the main application processor and limiting the data access of the wider system to high-level ML model outputs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is TinyML Sustainable? Assessing the Environmental Impacts of Machine Learning on Microcontrollers</title>
      <link>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/sustainabletinyml/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/sustainabletinyml/</guid>
      <description>The sustained growth of carbon emissions and global waste elicits significant sustainability concerns for our environment&amp;rsquo;s future. The growing Internet of Things (IoT) has the potential to exacerbate this issue. However, an emerging area known as Tiny Machine Learning (TinyML) has the opportunity to help address these environmental challenges through sustainable computing practices. TinyML, the deployment of machine learning (ML) algorithms onto low-cost, low-power microcontroller systems, enables on-device sensor analytics that unlocks numerous always-on ML applications. This article discusses the potential of these TinyML applications to address critical sustainability challenges. Moreover, the footprint of this emerging technology is assessed through a complete life cycle analysis of TinyML systems. From this analysis, TinyML presents opportunities to offset its carbon emissions by enabling applications that reduce the emissions of other sectors. Nevertheless, when globally scaled, the carbon footprint of TinyML systems is not negligible, necessitating that designers factor in environmental impact when formulating new devices. Finally, research directions for enabling further opportunities for TinyML to contribute to a sustainable future are outlined.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
