<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A²R Lab</title>
    <link>https://a2r-lab.github.io/authors/zacharymanchester/</link>
    <description>Recent content on A²R Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; {year} Brian Plancher</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://a2r-lab.github.io/authors/zacharymanchester/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://a2r-lab.github.io/authors/zacharymanchester/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a2r-lab.github.io/authors/zacharymanchester/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The 2025 Summer School on Optimization for Robotics</title>
      <link>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/optrobsummerschool2025ram/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/optrobsummerschool2025ram/</guid>
      <description>The 2025 Summer School on Optimization for Robotics took place on 14–18 July 2025 at the University of Patras in Patras, Greece. The event brought together researchers, students, and practitioners from across the world to learn, exchange ideas, and gain hands-on experience at the forefront of optimization methods for robotics. Overall, we had 89 total participants (∼7% undergraduate, ∼8% industry/engineer/faculty, ∼18% masters, and ∼66% Ph.D.) from more than 20 countries spanning four continents. The weeklong program featured a balanced mix of lectures, plenary talks, daily practical sessions, live demos, and social activities. The lectures covered foundational and advanced topics in optimization for planning, control, and learning in robotics, while the plenary speakers provided broad perspectives on emerging research directions and industrial applications.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Code Generation and Conic Constraints for Model-Predictive Control on Microcontrollers with Conic-TinyMPC</title>
      <link>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/conictinympc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/conictinympc/</guid>
      <description>We extend TinyMPC, an open-source, high-speed solver targeting low-power embedded control applications, to provide support for second-order cones, as well as &lt;code&gt;C++&lt;/code&gt; code generation from &lt;code&gt;Python&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;MATLAB&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;Julia&lt;/code&gt; for easy deployment. Microcontroller benchmarks show that our solver provides up to a two-order-of-magnitude speedup, ranging from 10.6x to 142.7x, over state-of-the-art embedded solvers on QP and SOCP problems, and enables us to fit order-of-magnitude larger problems in memory. We validate our solver&amp;rsquo;s deployed performance through simulation and hardware experiments, including conically-constrained trajectory tracking on a 27g Crazyflie quadrotor. To get started with Conic-TinyMPC, visit our documentation, examples, and the open-source codebase at &lt;a href=&#34;https://tinympc.org/&#34;&gt;tinympc.org&lt;/a&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing at All Scales: Edge (Non)linear Model Predictive Control from MCUs to GPUs</title>
      <link>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/optimizingatallscales/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/optimizingatallscales/</guid>
      <description>In our recent works, by leveraging a combination of parallelism, approximation, and structure exploitation, we have enabled and accelerated (nonlinear) trajectory optimization solvers for real-time performance on non-standard computational hardware, ranging from microcontrollers (MCUs) to graphical processing units (GPUs). This has led to real-time MPC onboard an MCU powered 27g quadrotor for dynamic obstacle avoidance, as well as simulated whole-body nonlinear MPC at kHz rates for a GPU powered manipulator for high speed trajectory tracking.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TinyMPC: Model-Predictive Control on Resource-Constrained Microcontrollers</title>
      <link>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/tinympc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/tinympc/</guid>
      <description>Model-predictive control (MPC) is a powerful tool for controlling highly dynamic robotic systems subject to complex constraints. However, MPC is computationally demanding, and is often impractical to implement on small, resource-constrained robotic platforms. We present TinyMPC, a high-speed MPC solver with a low memory footprint targeting the microcontrollers common on small robots. Our approach is based on the alternating direction method of multipliers (ADMM) and leverages the structure of the MPC problem for efficiency. We demonstrate TinyMPC both by benchmarking against the state-of-the-art solver OSQP, achieving nearly an order of magnitude speed increase, as well as through hardware experiments on a 27 g quadrotor, demonstrating high-speed trajectory tracking and dynamic obstacle avoidance.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constrained Unscented Dynamic Programming</title>
      <link>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/cudp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a2r-lab.github.io/publication/cudp/</guid>
      <description>We build on recent work on Unscented Dynamic Programming (UDP) - which eliminates dynamics derivative computations in DDP - to support general nonlinear state and input constraints using an augmented Lagrangian. The resulting algorithm has the same computational cost as first-order penalty-based DDP variants, but can achieve constraint satisfaction to high precision without the numerical ill-conditioning associated with penalty methods.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
